<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="ars-ak47">
		<text>AK-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak47_camo1">
		<text>Camouflaged AK-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak47_m1">
		<text>Mini-Dragunov AK-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks47">
		<text>AKS-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak74">
		<text>AK-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks74">
		<text>AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks74_m1">
		<text>AKS-74 (Kobra)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks74_m1_camo1">
		<text>Camouflaged AKS-74 (Kobra)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak74m">
		<text>AK-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak101">
		<text>AK-101</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak102">
		<text>AK-102</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak103">
		<text>AK-103</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak104">
		<text>AK-104</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak105">
		<text>AK-105</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak107">
		<text>AK-107</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak108">
		<text>AK-108</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-akm">
		<text>AKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-akms">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aks74u_m1_camo1">
		<text>AKS-74U Shturmovik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-an94">
		<text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ak5">
		<text>Bofors AK5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aug_a1">
		<text>Steyr AUG A1 (AUG-77)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aug_a2">
		<text>Steyr AUG A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-famas_f1">
		<text>FAMAS F1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-famas_g2">
		<text>FAMAS G2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-famas_p3">
		<text>FAMAS Commando Prototype</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-fnc">
		<text>FN FNC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-g36c">
		<text>HK G36C (Compact\Commando)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-g36e">
		<text>HK G36E (Export)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-g36k">
		<text>HK G36K (Kurz)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-galil_ar">
		<text>IMI Galil AR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-galil_arm">
		<text>IMI Galil ARM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-galil_mar">
		<text>IMI Galil MAR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-hk416">
		<text>HK 416</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-lr300ml">
		<text>Z-M LR300 ML</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m4a1">
		<text>Colt M4A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m16a1">
		<text>Colt M16A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m16a2">
		<text>Colt M16A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m16a3">
		<text>Colt M16A3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m16a4">
		<text>Colt M16A4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-vz58">
		<text>CZ SA Vz.58</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-rk95">
		<text>Valmet RK 95</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-rk95_camo1">
		<text>Camouflaged Valmet RK 95 </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sg550">
		<text>SIG SG550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sg551">
		<text>SIG SG551</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sg552">
		<text>SIG SG552 Commando</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-xm8">
		<text>HK XM8</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-xm177e2">
		<text>Colt XM177E2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-mg36">
		<text>HK MG36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-rpk74">
		<text>RPK-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-xm8_para">
		<text>HK XM8 Automatic Rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aps">
		<text>APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-beretta92">
		<text>Beretta 92</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-cz52">
		<text>CZ 52</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-deagle">
		<text>Desert Eagle .50AE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-fort12">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-glock18c_sk1">
		<text>Glock 18C</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-glock18c_sk2">
		<text>Glock 18C Expert</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-gsh18">
		<text>GSh-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m1911a1">
		<text>Colt Government M1911A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m1935hp_mk3">
		<text>FN Browning Hi-Power M1935 Mk.III</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-mp444-9x18">
		<text>MP-444 Bagira 9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-mp444-9x19">
		<text>MP-444 Bagira 9x19</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-oc33">
		<text>OTs-33 Pernach</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-p38">
		<text>Walther P38</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-p99">
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-p220">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-pm">
		<text>Makarov PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-tt33">
		<text>TT-33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-usp45c">
		<text>HK USP-45 Compact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-m1935">
		<text>FN Browning M1935 Hi-Power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sayga12k">
		<text>Saiga-12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ppd40">
		<text>PPD-40</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-ppsh41">
		<text>PPSh-41</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sr25_mk11_mod0">
		<text>KAC SR-25 Mk 11 MOD 0</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-hk417">
		<text>HK417 Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-galatz">
		<text>IMI Galatz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sg550sr">
		<text>SIG SG 550 Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-vss">
		<text>VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-val">
		<text>AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-l85a2">
		<text>Enfield L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-mp5a2">
		<text>HK MP5A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-acog">
		<text>ACOG Optical Scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-aug_a1_scope">
		<text>Swarovski Optical Scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-g36_scope">
		<text>Hensoldt ZF Optical Scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-scope1">
		<text>Barska Optical Scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_9_p">
		<text>M9-P Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_762_p">
		<text>M7.62-P Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_9_pb">
		<text>6P9 Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_545_ar">
		<text>M5.45-A Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_556_ar">
		<text>M5.56-A Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_762_ar">
		<text>M7.62-A Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_762_pms">
		<text>M7.62-PMS Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-sil_1143_p">
		<text>M11.43-P Silencer </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-50_ae">
		<text>.50 AE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x25_p">
		<text>7.62x25mm P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x25_ps">
		<text>7.62x25mm PS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x39_fmj">
		<text>7.62x39mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x39_ap">
		<text>7.62x39mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x51_fmj">
		<text>7.62x51mm NATO</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ars-7.62x51_ap">
		<text>7.62x51mm NATO AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47">
		<text>The AK-47 (Avtomat Kalashnikova obraztsa 1947 goda, or Kalashnikov assault rifle model 1947) is one of the most famous firearms in the world, chambered for the 7.62x39mm cartridge. This weapon is a true classic that's known all over the world, shown in countless TV shows, movies, and computer games. It is valued in the Zone for its reliability, able to work in flawlessly in extremely hostile environments; it's also a very simple firearm, easy to use and maintain. It can be found in both the hands of rookie and veteran stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47_camo1">
		<text>This AK-47 has had a custom camoflauge pattern applied, done with stencils and paint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47_m1">
		<text>The Mini Dragunov is a variant of the AK-47 that was developed and made by Romanian gunsmiths. It is, in essence, an AK-47 that has been modified to certain specifications, giving it increased accuracy - allowing it to function as an sniper rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks47">
		<text>The AKS-47 (Avtomat Kalashnikova skladnoy obraztsa 1947 goda, or Kalashnikov folding assault rifle model 1947) is a variant of the AK-47 that was developed for the Soviet Airborne Forces. It's considerably lighter than a regular AK-47, and takes up less space if the stock isn't unfolded - making it a better option for paratroopers, or anyone who wants a more portable version of the AK-47.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak74">
		<text>The AK-74 (Avtomat Kalashnikova obraztsa 1974 goda, or Kalashnikov assault rifle model 1974) is the successor to the AK-74, chambered for the 5.45x39mm cartridge. Like its predecessor, it's valued in the Zone for its reliability, able to work in flawlessly in extremely hostile environments; it's also a very simple firearm, easy to use and maintain. It can be found in both the hands of rookie and veteran stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74">
		<text>The AKS-74 (Avtomat Kalashnikova skladnoy obraztsa 1974 goda, or Kalashnikov folding assault rifle model 1974) is the successor to the AKS-47, chambered for the 5.45x39mm cartridge. Like the AKS-47, this weapon fills in the same niche: it was developed for the Soviet Airborne Forces, designed to be lighter and more portable - the AKS-74 takes up less space if its stock is folded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74_m1">
		<text>An AKS-74 with a EKP-8-02 Kobra collimator sight installed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74_m1_camo1">
		<text>An AKS-74 with both a EKP-8-02 Kobra collimator sight installed and a custom-made camoflauge pattern applied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak74m">
		<text>A modernized version of the AK-74 assault rifle, officially adopted by the Russian Army in the early 1990s. It differs from older versions of the AK-74 by implementing all of the improvements made for the other AK-74 variants into one unified design, having both a mounting bracket for optical sights and a folding stock. This rifle is also good for night outings in the Zone since it's completely black and non-reflective.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak101">
		<text>This assault rifle, as well as the entire 100x series of Kalashnikov assault rifles, is specifically meant for the export market. The AK-101 is a variant of the AK-74M that's been modified to use the 5.56x45 NATO cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak102">
		<text>The AK-102 is a shortened carbine variant of the AK-101. Compared to the AK-101, the AK-102 is considerably lighter and more comfortable to use - it's also unfailingly reliable, making it an excellent carbine assault rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak103">
		<text>This assault rifle, as well as the entire 100x series of Kalashnikov assault rifles, is specifically meant for the export market. The AK-103 is a variant of the AK-74M that's been modified to use the 7.62x39mm cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak104">
		<text>The AK-104 is a shortened carbine variant of the AK-103. Compared to the AK-103, the AK-104 is considerably lighter and more comfortable to use - it's also unfailingly reliable, making it an excellent carbine assault rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak105">
		<text>The AK-105 is a shortened carbine variant of the AK-74M. Compared to the AK-74M, the AK-105 is considerably lighter and more comfortable to use - it's also unfailingly reliable, making it an excellent carbine assault rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak107">
		<text>The AK-107 is a further development of the AK-74M, chambered for the same 5.45x39mm cartridge. It's equipped with a new gas system that has considerably better performance, making its recoil easier to manage - thus improving its accuracy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak108">
		<text>The AK-108 is a carbine variant of the AK-107 that's meant for the export market, featuring the same improvements in the gas system the AK-107 has. It's also chambered for 5.56x45mm NATO, and like the AK-104 and AK-105, it's very light and reliable - making it an excellent choice for a carbine assault rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_akm">
		<text>The AKM (Avtomat Kalashnikova modernizirovanny, or Kalashnikov's Automatic Rifle Modernised) is an improved version of the AK-47 that has several design revisions that improve its performance. Like the AK-47, the AKM is one of the most famous firearms in the world, chambered for the 7.62x39mm cartridge. This weapon is a true classic that's known all over the world, shown in countless TV shows, movies, and computer games. It is valued in the Zone for its reliability, able to work in flawlessly in extremely hostile environments; it's also a very simple firearm, easy to use and maintain. It can be found in both the hands of rookie and veteran stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_akms">
		<text>The AKM is an improved version of the AK-47 incorporating numerous design improvements. The AKMS is the variant of the AKM that was made for the Soviet Airborne Forces - it is almost the same weapon as the AKS-47, using the same 7.62x39mm cartridge, but it uses the design improvements introduced in the AKM.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74u">
		<text>The AKS-74U is a shortened carbine version of the AKS-74, designed from the ground-up to give vehicle crews, special forces, rear-echelone support units, and vehicle crews a compact and reliable assault rifle chambered for the 5.45x39mm cartridge. This weapon is somewhat unique because it bridges the gap between submachine guns and assault rifles - it is as light as an SMG, but it uses an intermediate cartridge. The AKS-74U excels in close-quarters and urban combat - and the 5.45x39mm cartridge packs a fair amount of punch, but the AKS-74U tends to overheat easily if you fire it in bursts a lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74u_m1_camo1">
		<text>This AKS-74U has been extensively modified; it has an EKP-8-02 Kobra sight attached, a hand-made camoflauge pattern applied, and a longer barrel; the longer barrel allows the installation of a GP-25 Kostyor grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_an94">
		<text>The AN-94 (Avtomat Nikonova 1994 goda, or Nikonov's assault rifle model 1994) is a rifle with a long history; originally intended as a replacement for the AK-74, the AN-94 is a very ambitious design that has several unique features that set it apart, such as a very precise two-round burst mode with a very gentle recoil impulse that feels like that only one round is being fired. Sadly, the AN-94 is a massively complex weapon - it can jam fairly easily if not taken care of properly, and it's much more of a hassle to maintain than an AK. Like the AK-74, it's chambered for the 5.45x39mm cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak5">
		<text>The Bofors AK 5 is variant of the FN FNC rifle that's the current service rifle of the Swedish Army, chambered for the 5.56x45mm NATO cartridge. It has numerous differences if compared FN FNC - mostly modifications to help the weapon work better in Sweden's subartic climate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a1">
		<text>A Steyr AUG bullpup rifle with an Swarovski 1.5 optical sight attached.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a2">
		<text>An improved variant of the the Steyr AUG bullpup rifle that has an integrated Picatinny rail attachment system, which is compatiable with any optical sight that has a compatible mount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_f1">
		<text>The FAMAS F1 is the first iteration of the FAMAS series of French-designed bullpup rifles. Its high rate of fire, decent accuracy, and good ergonomics coming from its good bullpup design have made it quite popular among foreign firearm enthusiasts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_g2">
		<text>A later variant of the FAMAS bullpup rifle that adheres to NATO-specific standards. One of the major revisions is that the original proprietary magazine was replaced with a 30 round STANAG magazine. The revised design also includes better ergonomics. This weapon is quite popular among foreign firearm enthusiasts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_p3">
		<text>A very rare prototype of the FAMAS Commando bullpup rifle. No one knows how this exceedingly rare prototype has managed to get to the Zone. (start here for your first session on 11/17/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_fnc">
		<text>The Belgian FN FNC, originally developed and designed in the late 1970s, has been largely used by police agencies from various countries, such as the USA. It's one of the more unknown firearms chambered for the 5.56x45mm NATO cartridge - not nearly as well-known as the M16 and such; those who have used it can testify to its excellent reliability, ergonomics. Despite this, one of the main reasons of its obscurity is the fact that its specific niche has been filled in by other rifles, which explains why this specific assault rifle is largely unknown. However, the Bofors Ak 5, a modified version of the FN FNC is the most well-known iteration of the FN FNC, which currently serves as the current service rifle for the Swedish Army. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_g36">
		<text>The G36 assault rifle was developed by German company Heckler und Koch GmbH in early 1990s under the HK 50 designation. In 1995, the G36 was officially adopted by German Army, and in 1999 it was officially adopted by Spanish Armed Forces. The G36 is one of the best post-Cold War era assault rifles - it's ergonomic, accurate and reliable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_g36c">
		<text>A modified variant of the G36 assault rifle that's shorter, making it carbine. It also comes with a Picatinny rail attachment system by default, allowing you to attach any compatible optical sights to it. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_g36e">
		<text>A variant of the G36 rifle that's meant for the export market. Its key difference is that it doesn't come with the Hensoldt optical sight that comes with the regular G36, having only iron sights and Picatinny rail mounts that can accept any compatible optical sight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_g36k">
		<text>The G36K is the carbine variant of the G36, having both a shorter barrel and a Picatinny rail system that can accept any compatible optical sights.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_ar">
		<text>The Galil is an Israeli assault rifle that has served as one of the Israel Defense Forces's service rifles for decades. Inspired by the Kalashnikov both in form and function, it's a reliable and unpretentious weapon. It also includes a built-in bottle opener near the front handguard - so if you're feeling thristy, you can use that to open a bottle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_arm">
		<text>The Galil ARM is the light machine gun variant of the Galil, equipped with a folding bipod, carrying handle, and a larger handguard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_mar">
		<text>A carbine variant of the Galil assault rifle that's more compact and portable, making it ideal for vehicle crews or rear echelon personnel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_hk416">
		<text>The HK 416 assault rifle is similar to the AR-15 assault rifle, but it has one key difference: it has a revised short-stroke gas piston system that's borrowed from the HK G36 assault rifle. (start here for your second session on 11/22/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_lr300ml">
		<text>The LR-300 is a revised design of the AR-15 that has several noticeable improvements, such as a unique, delayed semi-direct gas impingement system; this innovation gives the LR-300 better performance, giving it more controllable recoil impulse and better accuracy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m4a1">
		<text>A carbine variant of the M16A3 that has a long and varied history; the M4 carbine was officially introduced in the early 1990s after demand for a more compact version of the M16 rifle soared - specifically coming from troops deployed in Somalia during the Battle of Mogadishu. Troops needed a smaller version of the M16 rifle, and the M4 Carbine was made to meet that demand. Other carbines based on the M16/AR design existed during this time, such as the CAR-15, but were only made in small numbers. Like the M16A3, the M4 carbine has either fully automatic or single-fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a1">
		<text>By the early 1970s, the M16 rifle was a fully-fledged combat rifle with a number of significant advantages (and, of course, some disadvantages). Compared to its main rival, the Kalashnikov assault rifle, the M16 was more accurate, more comfortable to use, and easy to handle. On the other hand, the M16 required much more careful maintenance, and better quality ammunition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a2">
		<text>A later development of the M16 rifle, officially replacing the M16A1. If compared to the M16A1 - the A2 has a heavier barrel, a three-round burst mode instead of fully automatic, and a 30 round STANAG magazine instead of the 20 round one the M16A1 originally originally came with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a3">
		<text>A later development of the M16 rifle that's a variant of the M16A2 rifle with one major difference - instead of a three-round burst mode, it has fully automatic fire. Besides this, there's very little difference between the A2 and A3.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a4">
		<text>The A4 is the latest iteration of the M16/AR rifle that serves as the current service rifle of the US Army. The A4 is basically an improved A2, having the same design revisions but with the addition of a Picatinny rail system so that a wide range of optical scopes (or other similar equipment) can be attached to the rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_vz58">
		<text>The vz. 58 is an assault rifle of Czech design, and one of the more unique weapons that originally comes from the Warsaw Pact - it uses 7.62x39mm, but it's not a derivative of the Kalashnikov in any way besides that. Don't let the vz. 58's resemblance to the Kalashnikov fool you - it is an entirely unique design, sharing no parts with the AK-47/AKM.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_rk95">
		<text>The Valmet RK 95 is an improved version of the RK 62; both designs are copies of the AK-47 with numerous improvements applied. The RK 95's specific improvements include better ergonomics and better compatibility with components that can be attached via rail systems or mounts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_rk95_camo1">
		<text>The Valmet RK 95 is an improved version of the RK 62; both designs are copies of the AK-47 with numerous improvements applied. The RK 95's specific improvements include better ergonomics and better compatibility with components that can be attached via rail systems or mounts.  Additionally, this RK 95 has had a custom camoflauge pattern applied, done with stencils and paint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sg550">
		<text>The SIG SG 550 is the current service rifle of the Swiss Army, developed in the early 1980s to replace SIG 540. Comparing the SG 550 to a Swiss-made watch isn't farfetched - it's a firearm with fantastic engineering behind it. It's highly ergonomic, accurate, and reliable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sg551">
		<text>The SIG SG 551 is a carbine version of the SG 550. The SG 551 is a good compromise between the SG 550 and the SG 552, making it ideal if you want something that's shorter and lighter - but still accurate at long ranges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sg552">
		<text>The SIG SG 552 is a carbine version of the SG 550. It's smaller than the SG 551 carbine, so the SG 552 is a good choice if you want something that's small and light. (start here for your second session on 11/28/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_xm8">
		<text>The HK XM8 is an experimental assault rifle that's inspired by the HK G36. It nearly replaced the M16A2 when it was being evaluated by the US Army during trials, but failed to pass the test. Regardless, this weapon is exceedingly rare - and its ergonomics, accuracy, and reliability are exceptional.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_xm177e2">
		<text>The XM177E2 is an experimental carbine based on the M16/AR-15 rifle that was developed as a improved version of the CAR-15 carbine. It was only made in small numbers and mostly used by US Army spec ops units.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_mg36">
		<text>The HK MG36 is a light machine gun that's based on the HK G36 assault rifle. Because of its intended role, it comes with a 100 round drum magazine instead of the 30 round one that the HK G36 normally comes with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_rpk74">
		<text>The RPK-74 (Ruchnoy Pulemyot Kalashnikova 1974 goda, or Kalashnikov's hand-held machine model 1974) is a light machine gun that's based on the AK-74 assault rifle. Because of its intended role, it comes with a 75 round drum magazine instead of the 30 round one that the AK-74 normally comes with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_xm8_para">
		<text>The HK XM8 Automatic Rifle is a light machine gun that's based on the experimental HK XM8 assault rifle. Because of its intended role, it comes with a drum magazine that has a large capacity and a heavier barrel instead of the 30 round magazine that the HK XM8 normally comes with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aps">
		<text>The APS pistol was developed during the late 1940s and early 1950s by Igor Y. Stechkin and adopted by the Soviet Army in 1951; the Makarov PM also finalized development and trials during this time, so the Makarov was formally adopted around the same time the APS pistol was. The APS (Avtomaticheskiy Pistolet Stechkina, or Automatic Stechkin Pistol) was intended as a personal self-defense weapon for specific categories of soldiers and officers who were not allowed to carry an automatic rifle or carbine, giving them a means of defense.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_beretta92">
		<text>The Beretta 92 is an Italian-designed pistol. It has been officially adopted by the US Army under the Beretta M9 designation, although the Beretta 92 pistols that have made it into the Zone are not the ones made to the specifications of the US Army. The Beretta 92 series of pistols has earned the reputation of being quite reliable, but somewhat bulky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_cz52">
		<text>The CZ 52 was designed and developed by both Jan and Jaroslav Kratochvil in 1952 and served as the standard service sidearm of the Czechoslovak People's Army until 1982. The CZ 52 is simple and reliable, chambered for the same round the TT-33 uses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_deagle">
		<text>The Desert Eagle is a highly controversial pistol, developed by IMI and originally meant for the Israel Defense Forces, that has been featured in countless movies and games; this has made the Desert Eagle immensely popular. This pistol is fairly rare, and it uses a rotary bolt locking system, using the energy of the propellant gases from the barrel for cycling the weapon. The Desert Eagle is a very powerful pistol, with tremendous recoil.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_fort12">
		<text>The Fort-12 is an Ukrainian-made pistol adopted as a replacement for the obsolete Makarov PM The basic ammunition for this pistol was the already available and well mastered 9x18mm cartridge, but the new pistol had to provide more accuracy and firepower than the PM (due to larger magazine capacity). In essence, the Fort-12 is a revamped version of the Czech CZ-83 pistol; a CZ-83 served as the original testbed prototype for the Fort-12, and the necessary equipment for production was purchased in the Czech Republic. (start here for your second session on 12/3/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_glock18c_sk1">
		<text>The Glock 18 pistol (the number in Glock's naming scheme normally indicates how many rounds the weapon's magazine can hold - in this case, 18) was developed by the Austrian company Glock for the Austrian Army, and it was the first pistol made by Glock. Nevertheless, the pistol was extremely successful, reliable and comfortable, and was adopted by the Austrian Army. This variant has a three-round burst mode, along with a semi-automatic mode.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_glock18c_sk2">
		<text>The Glock 18 pistol (the number in Glock's naming scheme normally indicates how many rounds the weapon's magazine can hold - in this case, 18) was developed by the Austrian company Glock for the Austrian Army, and it was the first pistol made by Glock. Nevertheless, the pistol was extremely successful, reliable and comfortable, and was adopted by the Austrian Army. This variant is equipped with a 31-round magazine and a fully automatic firing mode, along with a semi-automatic mode.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_gsh18">
		<text>The GSh-18 pistol was developed in the late 1990s at the Tula Instrument Engineering Design Bureau, under the supervision of famous weapons designers Vasiliy P. Gryazev and Arkadiy S. Shipunov. The number 18 in the name denotes the magazine capacity. The GSh-18's advantages include good ergonomics and light weight, large magazine capacity, and good accuracy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m1911a1">
		<text>This pistol, the legendary Colt 1911 set the standard for all handgun designs when it was introduced over a century ago. It's still in service in a number of countries and in numerous branches of the US Armed Forces. It should be noted that both before and now, pistols of this design are produced not only by Colt - they are produced by dozens, if not hundreds of companies all over the world; there are many iterations of the Colt 1911 that are still being made, including the original version of the Colt 1911 made by John Browning's company.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m1935hp_mk3">
		<text>The FN Model Hi-Power Mark III is a modernized variant of the FN Browning Hi-Power pistol. The FN Browning Hi-Power pistol has been produced in numerous iterations since 1935 and has served as the standard pistol for numerous armies, such as the Canadian Armed Forces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_mp444-9x18">
		<text>The MP-444 Bagira pistol was designed and developed by the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant and was intended to replace the Makarov PM, but it only did so in a limited capacity - the MP-443 Grach has mostly superseded the Bagira. The MP-444 uses a short-stroke gas piston system instead of straight blowback. There are numerous variants of the MP-444, each one chambered for a specific cartridge - this one is chambered for 9x18mm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_mp444-9x19">
		<text>The MP-444 Bagira pistol was designed and developed by the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant and was intended to replace the Makarov PM, but it only did so in a limited capacity - the MP-443 Grach has mostly superseded the Bagira. The MP-444 uses a short-stroke gas piston system instead of straight blowback. There are numerous variants of the MP-444, each one chambered for a specific cartridge - this one is chambered for 9x19mm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_oc33">
		<text>The OTs-33 pistol was developed in the mid-1990s by TsKIB SOO (Central Design and Research Bureau of Sporting and Hunting Arms), under the direction of Igor Y. Stechkin. The OTs-33 was meant to replace the obsolete and long-discontinued Stechkin APS pistol - a weapon also developed by Igor Y. Stechkin. The OTs-33 pistol is an automatic weapon, based on a free-floating bolt action. To reduce percieved recoil, the barrel of the pistol is movable. At the end of the recoil cycle, the bolt picks up the massive barrel, and due to its inertia, the bolt is pre-braked before it collides with the frame in the rearmost position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_p38">
		<text>The Walther P38 was developed in the second half of the 1930s, designed from the ground up as an army pistol. Sweden purchased a small number of Walther P38's in pistols in 1938, and in 1940, this pistol was officially adopted by the Wehrmacht - officially designated as the Pistole 38. It was widely used during World War II. Being a semi-automatic, double-action pistol - the Walther P38 works by harnessing the energy from its recoil to help cycle itself - with a short travel time for the barrel while it recoils, giving it a snappy, but controllable recoil impulse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_p99">
		<text>Carl Walther GmbH Sportwaffen started the development of the P99 pistol in 1994. The main objective was to create a modern pistol for police and self-defense, capable of achieving greater commercial success than its predecessor, the P88, which, despite its excellent performance, was too expensive. The P99 was completed by 1996, and the result was quite successful. It has excellent ergonomics, good reliability, and is available in several variants - each variant differing in terms of specific features they have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_p220">
		<text>The SIG P220 was designed and developed by SIG Sauer in the 1970s as a response to a request for a new standard pistol for the Swiss Army; the one that was in service before the P220 was of exceptional quality, but very costly to produce and technologically obsolete. According to the army's requirements, the new pistol had to have the high reliability, accuracy, and low weight that all Swiss firearms are traditionally known for. The SIG P220 has a self-loading trigger mechanism, and it's also far less expensive to produce than the P210. After the P220 had finished development in the mid 1970s, it was officially by the Swiss Army, given the official designation Pistole 75. Like most modern pistols, the P220 pistol uses recoil energy for reloading, and it has a short travel time for the barrel, giving it a snappy but controllable recoil impulse. The barrel is locked by a modified Browning locking system, with one massive lug on the breech block behind the ejection port.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_pb">
		<text>The PB silenced pistol (given the GRAU index designation 6P9) was based upon the Makarov PM pistol during its development. Its intended for use by army reconnaissance teams and KGB personnel, and was adopted in 1967. The pistol uses an integral silencer, and unlike most similar systems, the silencer is made of two parts. This allows the gun to be carried and stored with the front of the silencer removed, and the front of the silencer to be quickly installed on the gun before use. In this case, the pistol is still safe for the shooter to fire with the silencer removed, which is important in critical situations. (start here for your second session on 12/9/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_pm">
		<text>The Makarov pistol was created in response to the Soviet Army's demand to develop a new self-defense pistol for officers. Compared to the TT-33, the Makarov is more compact and safer to handle, having an actual safety that works properly - and it also has greater stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_tt33">
		<text>The TT-33 (Tulsky, Tokarev, 1933) pistol, as its name implies, was developed at the Tula Gun Factory by the legendary Russian gunsmith Fyodor Tokarev and adopted by the Red Army in 1933. Based on the FN Model 1903, the TT pistol was an good weapon for its time, being powerful, reliable, and easy to maintain and repair. However, it has some disadvantages if compared to the FN Model 1903 - such as the lack of a safety and poor ergonomics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_usp45c">
		<text>The USP 45 Compact is a smaller version of the German designed USP-45 pistol. In general, the USP series of pistols are characterized by high reliability, excellent durability, and good accuracy. However, the USP series isn't without its faults - the original USP pistol is huge; even the Compact version is debatably too big. The USP's high center of gravity also makes it a bit awkward to handle, and good luck trying to conceal your USP on your person - trying to conceal even the Compact version is difficult. (start here for your second session on 12/10/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m1935">
		<text>The Browning Hi-Power pistol has manufactured by Belgian company FN Herstal since 1935. Having a development history that spans over a decade, the Browning Hi-Power started life as a prototype developed by John Browning, and then picked up and improved by Dieudonne Saive after John Browning's death - going through various iterations of development until the design finalized into what it is today. Throughout history, the Browning Hi-Power was in service with armies and police forces of many countries, including British Commonwealth countries (Great Britain, Canada...), and was produced in Belgium, Canada, Egypt and many other countries. The weapon is still in service in Great Britain, Belgium and many other countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sayga12k">
		<text>The Saiga shotguns are based upon Mikhail T. Kalashnikov's assault rifle design - having the same gas-operated, rotary bolt locking mechanism. Naturally, the bolt group and receiver were redesigned for use of hunting cartridges, the trigger mechanism was revised so that fully-automatic fire was removed, and gas regulator was added to the gas-operated mechanism to ensure reliable firing. The Saiga 12K version of the shotgun has a plastic forend, as well as a pistol grip and left-folding plastic buttstock from the AK-74M assault rifle. Standard sights include a sighting bar on the gas tube above the barrel. Ammunition is fed from special detachable box magazines of various capacities. The safety mechanism is similar to the one used the Kalashnikov series of assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ppd40">
		<text>The Degtyarev submachine gun was developed in the first half of the 1930s and officially adopted by various branches of the Red Army 1935, given the designation PPD-34. It was a typical first-generation submachine gun, with a wooden stock and extensive use of metal machining in production. Unfortunately, the current Red Army command did not understand the role of submachine guns, so the PPD-34, as well as its later variant - the PPD-34/38, were produced in small quantities and used mainly by NKVD border guard units. Before the Great Patriotic War, the PPD went under improvements in 1940 (with the final variant being designated the PPD-40), but its design proved to be unsuitable for wartime mass production. By the end of 1941, the PPD-40 was replaced by the newer, cheaper and more effective Shpagin submachine gun, the PPSh-41. The PPD-40 is based on free-floating bolt action. The weapon fires from the open bolt. (start here for your first session on 12/11/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ppsh41">
		<text>The PPSh-41 (Pistolet-pulemyot Shpagina-41, or Shpagin's machine-pistol-41) was created in 1941 to replace Degtyarev PPD-40 submachine gun; the PPD-40 was reliable and powerful, but it was time-consuming and expensive to produce, hence the need for a new SMG design. After being put through trials in 1941, it was adopted in the same year by the Red Army. The PPSh-41 was a simple and cheap to produce wartime weapon, and was produced in significant quantities - about 5 or 6 million PPSh-41's were produced during World War 2. Shortly after the war, the PPSh-41 was retired from the Red Army, but it was widely exported to pro-Soviet developing countries, and could be seen in Africa even in the 1980s. The advantages of the PPSh-41 SMG include its relatively high effective range, simplicity. and low cost. Sadly, the PPSh-41 does have its drawbacks: its heavy and bulky for an SMG, its high rate of fire needs practice to control effectively, and the PPSh-41 will accidentally discharge if you drop it onto a hard surface. (start here for your second session on 12/12/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sr25_mk11_mod0">
		<text>The SR-25 rifle was developed by Eugene Stoner (the main designer of the AR-15/M16 rifle) in early 1990s, when he was working with Knight's Armaments Co. of USA. The SR-25 (Stoner Rifle model 25) rifle is based on the AR-15 rifle design, but it has been modified to accept the 7.62x51mm NATO cartridge. The Mk.11 Mod.0 and XM110 rifles are designed to fire at enemy troops at ranges up to 800 meters. From a tactical point of view, these rifles are analogs of the Dragunov SVD sniper rifle, but they are distinguished by higher accuracy (normally due to better quality ammunition) and greater tactical flexibility. (start here for your first session on 12/12/23 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_hk417">
		<text>Автоматическая винтовка HK 417 калибра 7.62мм НАТО разработана на базе автоматической винтовки Heckler-Koch HK 416 калибра 5.56мм НАТО. Разработка винтовки НК 417 была начата в 2005 году на основе опыта, полученного войсками международной коалиции в Афганистане и Ираке, где в определенных условиях оружие калибра 5.56мм показало недостаточную эффективную дальность стрельбы и недостаточное пробивное и останавливающее действие малокалиберных пуль. Винтовки серии НК 417 пошли в серийное производство в 2007 или 2008 году, и предлагаются для вооружения армейских и полицейских сил. Винтовка HK 417 имеет модульную конструкцию, в значительной мере повторяющую конструкцию американской винтовки М16, с одним важным отличием - германская винтовка HK 417 имеет измененную систему газоотводной автоматики, использующую обычный газовый поршень с коротким рабочим ходом. Есть и ряд других отличий, однако все основные органы управления и метод разборки и сборки оружия унаследованы от М16. Оснащена оптическим прицелом кратности 6x.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_galatz">
		<text>Данная снайперская винтовка (в Армии Обороны Израиля - ЦАХАЛе известна под названием GALATZ) по сути, является переделкой автомата IMI Galil под более мощный патрон 7.62mm NATO (.308win). С точки зрения тактики, GALATZ ближе к таким образцам "оружия поддержки", как Российская СВД или немецкая G3-SG1, в отличие от "чисто снайперских" образцов, типа американских M24 или M40, или немецких Mauser 66 и 86, также применяемых Армией Обороны Израиля.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_svd">
		<text>В 1958 году ГРАУ (Главное Ракетно-Артиллерийское Управление) Генштаба Советской Армии объявило конкурс на создание самозарядной снайперской винтовки для Советской Армии. В конкурсе победил коллектив, возглавляемый Е.Драгуновым, и в 1963 году СВД (Снайперская винтовка Драгунова) была принята на вооружение СА. Специально для СВД был создан "снайперский" патрон с пулей со стальным сердечником, однако винтовка может использовать всю номенклатуру отечественных патронов 7.62х54R. Нужно отметить, что тактическая роль, которая отводилась и отводится винтовке СВД в Совесткой и Российской армиях отличается от традиционной роли "снайпера" в западном понимании этого термина. Винтовка СВД служит для увеличения дальности эффективного огня стрелкового отделения за пределами возможностей штатных автоматов, вплоть до расстояний в 600-700 метров. Самая распространённая снайперская винтовка в Зоне.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m1935">
		<text>Легендарный пистолет бельгийского производства, выпускавщийся с 1935-го года.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sg550sr">
		<text>Снайперская модификация винтовки SIG SG550.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_vss">
		<text>Винтовка снайперская специальная "Винторез" - точное и бесшумное оружие снайпера. В Зоне встречается крайне редко, из-за дороговизны и не самой высокой надёжности.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_val">
		<text>Автомат специальный "Вал" - бесшумный автомат для спецопераций.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_l85a2">
		<text>Английская штурмовая винтовка, принятая на вооружение в 1980-х годах. Винтовка L85A2 выполнена по схеме булл-пап. Автоматика на основе газоотводного механизма с коротким ходом газового поршня и трехпозиционным газовым регулятором (обеспечивающим стрельбу в обычных условиях, в условиях повышенной загрязненности и метание ружейных гранат со ствола).  Запирание ствола - традиционным поворотным затвором, имеющим 7 боевых упоров, за вкладыш ствольной коробки. Затворная рама перемещается внутри ствольной коробки на двух направляющих стержнях, не касаясь стенок, возвратная пружина расположена посередине между стрежнями и выше их. Рукоятка взведения зафиксирована на затворной раме справа и движется при стрельбе.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_mp5a2">
		<text>Немецкий пистолет-пулемёт HK MP5 (в данном случае вариант MP5A2 с фиксированным прикладом) принят на вооружение многих силовых структур различных стран мира. Своему успеху МР5 обязан, кроме весьма успешной маркетинговой политики фирмы, таким своим свойствам как надежность, удобство в обращении, высокая точность стрельбы.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_acog">
		<text>4-х кратный оптический прицел для винтовок НАТО.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a1_scope">
		<text>Линза оптического прицела винтовки Steyr AUG-77.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_g36_scope">
		<text>Линза оптического прицела винтовки G36.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_scope1">
		<text>Съёмный оптический прицел старого образца для винтовок M16A1\A2.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_9_p">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для пистолетов калибра 9мм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_p">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для пистолетов калибра 7.62мм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_9_pb">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для пистолета ПБ (6П9).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_545_ar">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для автоматов калибра 5.45мм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_556_ar">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для автоматов и винтовок калибра 5.56мм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_ar">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для автоматов и винтовок калибра 7.62мм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_pms">
		<text>Прибор малошумной стрельбы для винтовок калибра 7.62мм, в частности, для СВД.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_1143_p">
		<text>Прибор бесшумной стрельбы для пистолетов калибра 11.43мм (.45).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_50_ae">
		<text>Пистолетный патрон с пулей крупного калибра для пистолета Desert Eagle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x25_p">
		<text>Советский пистолетный патрон калибра 7.62мм. Простая цельнометаллическая пуля.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x25_ps">
		<text>Советский пистолетный патрон калибра 7.62мм. Пуля со стальным сердечником, улучшенная бронебойность.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x39_fmj">
		<text>Советский автоматный патрон калибра 7.62мм. Простая цельнометаллическая пуля.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x39_ap">
		<text>Советский автоматный патрон калибра 7.62мм. Пуля со стальным сердечником, улучшенная бронебойность.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x51_fmj">
		<text>Винтовочный боеприпас стандарта НАТО. Калибр - 7.62мм. Простая цельнометаллическая пуля.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x51_ap">
		<text>Винтовочный боеприпас стандарта НАТО. Калибр - 7.62мм. Пуля со стальным сердечником, улучшенная бронебойность.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>